

CONTACT

- 9284766538
- <u>saurabhnbhoyar@gmail.com</u>
- Pune,MH





EDUCATION

2021 - 2023

SPPU UNIVERSITY

- Master computer Application
- CGPA -7.77

2017-2020

GONDWANA UNIVERSITY

- Bachelor computer Application
- CGPA: 6.61

SKILLS

- PowerBi
- Azure
- Pyspark
- ML
- Al
- Python
- DataBricks
- AzureData lake
- Mysql
- Sql Server

CERTIFICATE

- Microsoft Ai Fundamentals
- Microsoft Azure Data engineer Associate, koening solution.
- Data Analytics ,Board Infinty
- python ML AI ,marvellous Institude

SAURABH BHOYAR

DATA ENGINEER

PROFILE

Currently working as a Big Data Developer/ Data Engineer with 2+ years of relevant and 3 years of overall in Software Development. Skilled & certified in Big Data (SQL, Python, PySpark, ML), Microsoft Azure (Azure Ai Fundamentals). Worked on various data environment like Azure Datafactory, Databricks, Azure Data lake Storage Gen 2. Solid history of developing the product, discovering errors, resolving defects, and ensuring client expectations are met with high-quality and lucrative software solutions. Passionate tech enthusiast with ability to adapt new technologies, can easily collab with developers, Stake- holder & project managers to accomplish milestones.Can use extension of modern Al tools such as Chat-GPT, Claude, and Gemini to speed up work with maximum efficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

INFOSYS

CAIP Application UBS Invesment Bank.(java/cloud Developer)

AUG 2021 - JUN 2022

- Migrating the existing project to Microsoft Azure with Azure services
- Upgrading the servers like Tomcat from 8.5 to Tomcat 9 in the project before migration.
- Setup the required setup in the Local, Dev, Test and Prod environments.
- FitBit Data Ingestion and Visualization.

JUN 2022- FEB 2023

- Involved in Requirement Analysis & preparation of Functional Design documents. FitBit Data Model creation.
- Using Azure etl to load data from stage to data warehouse.
- Applied transformations for data aggregation or categorization as per the needs of Visualization.
- · Created different charts and graphs to analyse data

CloudHarmony ETL Migration

FEB 23- PRESENT

- Spearheaded data integration and ETL service in the Azure ecosystem, offering similar functionalities implementation for data extraction, transformation (Apache Spark, Python), and seamless downstream delivery across channels over 200 ETL jobs.
- Executed robust data migration strategies with Azure Data Migration Service, ensuring smooth on-premises to cloud transfer for more than 20 databases within multiple regions.
- Managed large-scale big data, optimizing storage and governance strategies. Engineered a streamlined data pipeline for efficient ELT processes.
- Designed Denodo APIs for an effective data access layer. Orchestrated Azure resource management through laaC (Cloud Formation), optimizing PostgreSQL queries.
- Designed and implemented lambda jobs to ingest and integrate data.